Guide to the Records of the 7th Regiment 1767-1983 (bulk 1830-1947) MS 556
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV: Francis D. Landon, 1908-1918, 12600
  - Subseries 3: Camp Merritt, 1918-1919, 12664
    - Morale Office - John Gorman, 1919; 12717 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Morale Office - Matthew P. Halpin, 1919; 12716 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Morale Office - Curtis Harrington, 1918; 12715 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Morale Office - Ensign Ernest R. Holz, 1919; 12714 (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Morale Office - Grace W. Hurd, 1919; 12713 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Morale Office - Iron Steamboat Co., 1919; 12712 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Morale Office - Edwin Newall Lewis, 1919; 12711 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Morale Office - Mandalay Line, 1919; 12710 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Morale Office - Arthur McAleenan, 1919; 12709 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - Morale Office - Col. E. L. Munson, 1919; 12708 (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - Morale Office - Thomas H. Neary, 1919; 12707 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - Morale Office - Col. Charles M. O'Connor, Undated; 12706 (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - Morale Office - Pain's Fireworks Co., 1919; 12705 (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - Morale Office - Capt. F. Peterson, 1919; 12704 (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - Morale Office - Marian R. Ramsey, 1918; 12703 (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - Morale Office - Joseph Raycroft, 1918; 12702 (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - Morale Office - Alphonso Scerbo, 1919; 12701 (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - Morale Office - Shamrock Towing Co., 1919; 12700 (Box 27, Folder 36)
    - Morale Office - Mrs. E. M. Speer, 1919; 12699 (Box 27, Folder 37)
    - Morale Office - Maj. [ ] Sullivan, 1919; 12698 (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - Morale Office - Mrs. E. M. Townsend, 1918; 12697 (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - Morale Office - Winton J. White, 1919; 12696 (Box 27, Folder 40)
    - Morale Office -Whitehead & Hoag Co., 1918-1919; 12695 (Box 27, Folder 41)
    - Morale Office - B. C. Wooster, 1919; 12694 (Box 27, Folder 42)
    - Morale Office - Wynkoop Hallenbeck Crawford Co., 1919; 12693 (Box 27, Folder 43)
    - Morale Office - Memoranda Received, 1918 Dec.-1919 Mar.; 12692 (Box 27, Folder 44)
    - Morale Office - Memoranda from War Dept. Morale Branch, 1918-1919; 12691 (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - Morale Office - Memoranda Sent, 1918 Nov.-1919 Aug., undated; 12690 (Box 27, Folder 46)
    - Morale Office - [Internal Memorandum], 1919; 12689 (Box 27, Folder 47)
    - Morale Office - Orders and Circulars, 1918 Oct.-Nov.; 12688 (Box 27, Folder 48)
    - Morale Office - Weekly Morale Reports, 1918 Nov.-1919 Sept.; 12687 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Morale Office - War Dept. General Orders, 1918; 12686 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Morale Office - Minutes of Morale Committee, 1918; 12685 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Morale Office - [Proposed Designs for Children's Medal], [1918]; 12684 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Morale Office - Lists of Schools in Bergen County, NJ, [1919]; 12683 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Morale Office - Case of Pvt. Wm. Franklin, 1918-1919; 12682 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Morale Office - Distribution of Posters, Undated; 12681 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Morale Office - Schedule of Service Calls, 1918; 12680 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Morale Office - Bills & Receipts re Children's Medals, 1918-1919, undated; 12679 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Morale Office - [Returns of Personnel], 1919; 12678 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Morale Office - Distribution of Red Cross Packages & Xmas Trees, Undated; 12677 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Morale Office -Organizational Chart of Morale Agencies, 1918; 12676 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Morale Office - Booklet - Merritt Hall - Soldiers' Club, [1918]; 12675 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - [Notes for Booklet], [1918]; 12674 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Booklet - Naturalization Laws and Regulations, 1918; 12673 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Booklet - War Risk Insurance Act, 1919; 12672 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Petition of David Richard Gottlieb for Naturalization, 1919; 12671 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - List of Recreation and Entertainment Buildings at Camp Merritt, Undated; 12670 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - YMCA school Enrollment, [1919]; 12669 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Telephone Directories, 1919 Aug., undated; 12668 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - [Return of Garrison], 1918; 12667 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Sketch of [Shoulder Patch], Undated; 12666 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - Clipping, 1919; 12665 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Single Folder Subseries, 1909-1918, 12652
    - HQ, port of Embarkation, Hoboken NJ - Special Order, 1919 Nov. 4; 12663 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - War Department - General Orders, 1913, 1918; 12662 (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - New York National Guard - General Orders, 1914, 1915; 12661 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - 7th Regiment HQ - General Orders, 1909; 12660 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - Tables of Organization and Equipment, U.S. Army, 1918; 12659 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - Notebook, Undated; 12658 (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - Doggerel, Undated; 12657 (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - Clippings, 1914, 1918; 12656 (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - Advertisement for Rifle Scope, Undated; 12655 (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - Clippings of Maps from WWI era, 1914, 1915, 1916; 12654 (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - Blank Contour Sheets for map Drawing, Undated; 12653 (Box 28, Folder 34)
  - Maps, 12649
    Most of these are of the Pennsylvania - Maryland border, and were evidently used in conjunction with Map Problems. Other maps depict the Eastern and Western Fronts in the First World War, Fort Leavenworth and its environs, and locations in Central Europe.
    - Maps--Europe, Ft. Leavenworth and vicinity, Mexico, locations in U.S. (other than Pa-MD border), oversize contour sheets, 12651 (Box 86 (oversize))
    - Maps--Oversize and PA-MD Border, 12650 (Box 87 (oversize))
  - Pamphlets, 1908-1918, 12601
    - Barry, Lt. Walter M. Dreams, Joys & Sorrows of the 13th Infantry, [1918]; 12648 (Box 29)
    - Bedier, Joseph How Germany Seeks to Justify Her Atrocities, 1915; 12647 (Box 29)
    - Bjornstad, Capt. A.W. The German Army, 1916; 12646 (Box 29)
    - Burnham, Lt. Col. W. P. Army Service Schools - Annual Report, 1913; 12645 (Box 29)
    - Conger, Capt. [ ] Preparing Tactical Problems, 1916; 12644 (Box 29)
    - Eames, Capt. E. H. Military Maps Explained, 1908; 12643 (Box 29)
    - Eltinge, Capt. Le Roy Psychology of War, 1915; 12642 (Box 29)
    - Eltinge, Maj. Le Roy Notes on Cavalry, 1917; 12641 (Box 29)
    - Eltinge, Maj. Le Roy Field Fortifications and Demolitions, 1917; 12640 (Box 29)
    - Fiske, Capt. H. B. Some Notes on the Solution of Tactical Problems, 1916; 12639 (Box 29)
    - Fiske, Maj. H. B. Notes on Infantry, 1917; 12638 (Box 29)
    - Ford, Clyde Sinclair The Balkan Wars, 1915; 12637 (Box 29)
    - Hayne, Capt. P. T. Lectures on Cavalry, 1915; 12636 (Box 29)
    - Hitt, Capt. Parker Manual for the Solution of Military Ciphers, 1916; 12635 (Box 29)
    - Holbrook, Col. W. A. Notes Preliminary Conference on Conduct of War, 1916; 12634 (Box 29)
    - Hutchinson, Maj. James Notes on Military Map Reading, 1915; 12633 (Box 29)
    - Jarvis, N. S., M. D. The Medical Side of the Army Maneuvers in Texas, 1911; 12632 (Box 29)
    - Mauborgne, Lt. J. O. An Advanced Problem in Cryptography and its Solution, 1914; 12631 (Box 29)
    - Moore, Maj. G. D. The Casey Firing Problem, [1913]; 12630 (Box 29)
    - Morrison, Maj. John F. Lectures on Patrols, Advance Guards, and Outposts (2 copies), 1909; 12629 (Box 29)
    - Morrison, Maj. J. F. Applied Minor Tactics (2 copies), 1911; 12628 (Box 29)
    - Naylor, Capt. W. K. The Principles of Strategy as Illustrated by the Civil War, 1916; 12627 (Box 30)
    - Porter, Col. J. B. Suggested Forms for Military Passes, etc. as well as for Certain Military Agreements, such as Armistices, etc. (2 copies), 1914; 12626 (Box 30)
    - Porter, Col. John Biddle The Geneva and Hague Conventions, 1914; 12625 (Box 30)
    - Sherill, Capt. C. O. Military Map Reading, 1909; 12624 (Box 30)
    - Spaulding, Capt. George R. Notes on Bridges and Bridging, 1916; 12623 (Box 30)
    - Wadhams, Maj. Sanford H. Elements of Military Hygiene, 1914; 12622 (Box 30)
    - Warfield, Capt. A. B. Notes on Field Artillery, 1917; 12621 (Box 30)
    - [NY] Adjutant General Practical talk on Summer Maneuvers, 1912; 12620 (Box 30)
    - [Army Service Schools] Divisional Outposts, 1916; 12619 (Box 30)
    - [Army Service Schools] European Frontiers, Undated; 12618 (Box 30)
    - Playground and Recreation Association of America War Camp Community Service: The Second Six Months, [1918]; 12617 (Box 30)
    - [U. S. War Department] Facts of Interest Concerning the Military Resources of the United States, 1914; 12616 (Box 30)
    - [Army Service Schools] Ready Reference Notes for the Line Class in the Solution of Division and Brigade Problems Involving the Use of Signal Corps Units (2 copies), Undated; 12615 (Box 30)
    - [Army Service Schools] Instruction in Equitation, 1917; 12614 (Box 30)
    - [Army Service Schools] A Synopsis of "The Rifle in War", 1914; 12613 (Box 30)
    - [U. S. War Department] Manual of the Bayonet, 1913; 12612 (Box 30)
    - [Army Service Schools] Sample Map Maneuvers, 1915; 12611 (Box 30)
    - [Army Service Schools] Notes on Field Fortification, 1914; 12610 (Box 30)
    - [Army Service Schools] Regulations, 1913; 12609 (Box 30)
    - [Army Service Schools] A Study in Staff Supply, [1915]; 12608 (Box 30)
    - [Army Service Schools] Notes on Field Fortification, 1912; 12607 (Box 30)
    - [Gov't Printing Office] Secretary of War Garrison's Explanation of the Military Policy Recommended by Him and Approved by the President, [1915]; 12606 (Box 30)
    - [U. S. Army] Questions in Guard Manual for Privates for Orderlies and Color Sentinels, 1915; 12605 (Box 30)
    - [U. S. Army Signal Corps] Field Message Book (blank), Undated; 12604 (Box 30)
    - [7th Regiment] Bulletin for the use of Officers and Enlisted Men During the Connecticut Maneuver Campaign, 1912; 12603 (Box 30)
    - U. S. War Department Army Song Book, 1918; 12602 (Box 30)
- Series V: Robert M. Lester, 1942-1951, 12595
  This series contains the World War II era files of Lt. Robert M. Lester, who served in the New York State Guard, Headquarters and Service Company. Topics include 7th Regiment history, training, the Second Service Command Tactical School, and Camp Smith. The bulk of the material is memoranda and administrative items. Lester's collection of photographs can be found in Series XIV: Visual Materials.
  - Correspondence, Memos, 1942-1951; 12599 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Certificates, 1943-1945; 12598 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - "Outline of Talk to Officer Candidates", 1944; 12597 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - New York Guard Association, Delegates to Convention, 1945; 12596 (Box 31, Folder 4)
- Series VI: Armory, 1860-1888, 12584
  This series consists of materials relating to the building and maintenance of the 7th Regiment armories. Most of the material relates to the armory on Park Avenue and 66th Street, built in 1880. For other information see the reports of the Armory Committee under Committees, Series I: Headquarters.
  - Regulations of the National Guard Armory, 1860; 12594 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Inventory of Armory, 1861, 1886; 12593 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Seventh Regiment New Armory Fund, 1876-1880; 12592 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Proposed Acts and Laws re: New Armory, 1879, undated; 12591 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - List of "Work Done by the Regiment" on the Armory, 1893; 12590 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Account Book--Cash Book--New Armory Fund, 1876-1880; 12589 (Volume 302)
  - Account Book--Subscription Book--Armory Fund, [1877]; 12588 (Volume 303)
  - Visitors Book, 1860-1874; 12587 (Volume 304)
  - Visitors Book, 1881-1883; 12586 (Volume 305)
  - Guestbook, 1883-1888; 12585 (Volume 306)
- Series VII: Histories, 1831-1956, 12568
  This series contains various histories of the 7th Regiment, some of which are general regimental histories (primarily commemorative or promotional), and others histories or reminiscences of specific time periods, events, or designations of the regiment. The account of the Astor Place Riot is told from a man claiming to be both an instigator of the conflict and a member of 7th Regiment sent to suppress the riot.
  - 7th Regiment, 1908-1956, undated; 12583 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - 207th A.A.A. Group, 1945; 12582 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - 7th A.A.A. Battalion (A.W.) (2 copies), 1945; 12581 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - 771st A.A.A. Gun Battalion, Notes (3 copies), 1951; 12580 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - 7th Regiment- Specific Events/Items, 1953, 1961, undated; 12579 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - "Private Journal"/"Prison Diary" - Charleston Prison, Alexander Shaler, 1864; 12578 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - "American 'National Guards,' A Brief Memoir... by Henry O'Reilly", 1877; 12577 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - "Memoir of Camp Clinton", 1831; 12576 (Volume 307)
  - Camp Scott Diary, 1861; 12575 (Volume 308)
  - Account of 1849 Astor Place Riot (typescript), [1889]; 12574 (Volume 309)
  - "A Brief History of the Seventh Regiment", 1931; 12573 (Volume 310)
  - "History of the Seventh Regiment, 1889-1918" by DeWitt Clinton Falls (in 2 parts; 2 copies), 1932; 12572 (Volume 311)
  - Recollections of Wm. H Owen, written by Wm. H Owen Jr., 1938; 12571 (Volume 312)
  - "Reminiscence of the Flour Riot in 1837" (2 copies), Undated; 12570 (Volume 313)
  - "March of the 7th Regiment N.G.N.Y. to Washington" (typescript of 1861 sermon), Undated; 12569 (Volume 314)
- Series VIII: Scrapbooks, 1852-1946, 12522
  The scrapbooks in this collection contain various types of material including clippings, ephemera, photographs, correspondence, and cartoons. Some scrapbooks pertain to the regiment as a whole, other are scrapbooks of specific individuals, and some cover particular events or topics such as the regiment's centennial celebration, and the Croton Dam strike. Two scrapbooks from 1909 and 1912 document the 7th Regiment's participation in war games. The scrapbooks are arranged chronologically.
  - "Crystal Palace Album & Hippodrome Gazette", 1852-1857; 12567 (Volume 315)
  - Maj. Kenneth C. Miller, 1855-1865; 12566 (Volume 316)
  - DeWitt Clinton Falls, 1856-1892; 12565 (Volume 317)
  - Scrapbook, 1857-1860; 12564 (Volume 318)
  - Scrapbook, 1860-1862; 12563 (Volume 319)
  - Scrapbook, 1868-1872; 12562 (Volume 320)
  - Scrapbook (with orders), 1869; 12561 (Volume 321)
  - Scrapbook, 1869-1872; 12560 (Volume 322)
  - Scrapbook, 1872; 12559 (Volume 323)
  - Scrapbook, 1872-1878; 12558 (Volume 324)
  - Scrapbook, 1873-1878; 12557 (Volume 325)
  - Scrapbook, 1875-1876; 12556 (Volume 326)
  - Scrapbook, 1879-1886; 12555 (Volume 327)
  - Scrapbook, 1883-1887; 12554 (Volume 328)
  - Scrapbook, 1885-1890; 12553 (Volume 329)
  - Scrapbook, 1886-1889; 12552 (Volume 330)
  - Scrapbook, 1889; 12551 (Volume 331)
  - Scrapbook, 1889; 12550 (Volume 332)
  - [DeWitt Clinton Falls], [1891-1897]; 12549 (Volume 333)
  - [DeWitt Clinton Falls], 1891-1895; 12548 (Volume 334)
  - Scrapbook, 1893-1896; 12547 (Volume 335)
  - DeWitt Clinton Falls, 1898-1901; 12546 (Volume 336)
  - Spanish American War, 1898; 12545 (Volume 337)
  - Francis F. Spies, 1898-1899; 12544 (Volume 338)
  - Silas B. Brower, 1899-1900; 12543 (Volume 339)
  - Croton Dam Strike, 1900; 12542 (Volume 340)
  - Croton Dam Strike, 1900; 12541 (Volume 341)
  - DeWitt Clinton Falls, 1902-1905; 12540 (Volume 342)
  - DeWitt Clinton Falls, 1906-1908; 12539 (Volume 343)
  - Centennial Celebration, 1906; 12538 (Volume 344)
  - DeWitt Clinton Falls, 1908-1911; 12537 (Volume 345)
  - Maneuvers, 1909; 12536 (Volume 346)
  - DeWitt Clinton Falls, 1912-1916; 12535 (Volume 347)
  - Maneuvers, Connecticut, 1912; 12534 (Volume 348)
  - Union League Club, 1913; 12533 (Volume 349)
  - Mexican Border/ World War I, 1916; 12532 (Volume 350)
  - Warren G. Harding, [1923]; 12531 (Volume 351)
  - "The National Guard Alphabet"-- Cartoons, 1924-1929; 12530 (Volume 352)
  - DeWitt Clinton Falls, 1926-1932; 12529 (Volume 353)
  - [DeWitt Clinton Falls], compiler-- Cartoon Book, 1931-1934; 12528 (Volume 354)
  - Scrapbook, 1932-1933; 12527 (Volume 355)
  - DeWitt Clinton Falls, 1932-1937; 12526 (Volume 356)
  - "Kipling's Autobiography"-- Clippings, 1937; 12525 (Volume 357)
  - Scrapbook, 1937; 12524 (Volume 358)
  - Clippings, 1943-1946; 12523 (Volume 359)
- Series IX: Ephemera, 1820-1976, 12463
  This series includes primarily items related to 7th Regiment events, World War I, the 7th's Mexican border service, companies, and veterans. Material related to 7th Regiment events includes programs, tickets, announcements, and menus for various dinners, balls, excursions, celebrations, and concerts (1820-1964). World War I material contains instructional, promotional, and recruitment items from the Red Cross and other relief organizations, the armed services, the U.S. Food Administration, and various other sources. Ephemera related to the 7th's Mexican border service in 1916 is primarily newspaper clippings, also some New York State election material. Company ephemera mostly documents company events, such as dinners, parties, and entertainment. Veteran material is also mainly events related, especially annual dinners and reunions.
  Other material in this series includes 7th Regiment and National Guard recruitment items; pamphlets, brochures, flyers, posters, and circulars from various sources; Civil War broadsides that advertise amusements; training material; divine service and memorial programs; various ads and catalogs; election nominee slips and calling cards; postcards; non-military or 7th Regiment certificates; and newspaper clippings.
  - Events, 1820-1879; 12521 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Events, 1880-1887; 12520 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Events, 1888-1906; 12519 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Events--Centennial Celebration, 1906 May 6; 12518 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Events, 1908; 12517 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Events--Celebration of the 50th Anniversary of Departure for Washington, April 19, 1861, 1911; 12516 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Events, 1912-1916; 12515 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Events, 1918-1921; 12514 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Events, 1922-1937; 12513 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Events--Farewell Dinner, 207th Coast Artillery, 1940 Dec. 16; 12512 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Events, 1940-1947; 12511 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Events--Military Ball, 1948 Dec. 11; 12510 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Events, 1948-1964, undated; 12509 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - World War I--Circulars, Pamphlets, Flyers, 1916-1922, undated; 12508 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - World War I--Booklets, 1916-1918, undated; 12507 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - World War I--Booklets, 1918-1919, undated; 12506 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - World War I--Memorials, 1919, 1927, undated; 12505 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Mexican Border Service--Election Material, 1916, [1916]; 12504 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Mexican Border Service--Clippings, 1916, [1916]; 12503 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Mexican Border Service--Clippings, 1916, [1916]; 12502 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Mexican Border Service--Clippings, 1916, [1916]; 12501 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Co. B, 1863-1893; 12500 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Co. B, 1903-1949; 12499 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Co. C-I, 1833-1924; 12498 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Co. K-M, Various, 1879-1955; 12497 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Veterans Material, 1869-1935; 12496 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Veterans of the 7th Regiment, 1897-1952; 12495 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Veterans of the 7th Regiment, 1953-1967; 12494 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Recruiting Material, 7th Regiment, 1879, [1940s]; 12493 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Recruiting Material, National Guard, 1948, [1940s]; 12492 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets, Brochures, 1876-1976, undated; 12491 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Flyers, Posters, Circulars, 1948, undated; 12490 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Civil War Broadsides--Amusements, 1862; 12489 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Training Material, 1865-1866, 1918, 1944, undated; 12488 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Divine Services, Memorials, 1860-1872, 1903-1915; 12487 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Ads, Catalogs, 1934, 1951, undated; 12486 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Election Slips, Calling Cards, Postcards, 1889, undated; 12485 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Sketches, Undated; 12484 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Certificates, 1860, 1884, 1885, undated; 12483 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Blank Stationary, Undated; 12482 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Photostats--Civil War Recruitment Broadsides, Undated; 12481 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Clippings re: Col. William Kipp, 1908-1919; 12480 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 1865-1964, undated; 12479 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, 12478 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 12477 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 12476 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 12475 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 12474 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 12473 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 12472 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 12471 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, 12470 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 12469 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 12468 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Events--Centennial Celebration, 1906; 12467 (Volume 360)
  - Events--Various, 1908-1932; 12466 (Volume 361)
  - Events--Gen. Louis Fitzgerald, Retirement Testimonial, [c1898]; 12465 (Volume 362)
  - Resolutions of Thanks--Union League Club, 1913; 12464 (Volume 363)
- Series X: Music, 1862-1952, 12443
  This series includes primarily regimental sheet music, song books, and musical instruction, as well as administrative items for the Drum Corps and Band.
  - Song Sheets, 1909, undated; 12462 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Song Books, 1863, 1952, undated; 12461 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - 7th Regiment Song Book, 1914; 12460 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Program--Military Concert, Co. G, 1922; 12459 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Bugle Instruction and Sounds, 1862, undated; 12458 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - "Get in Step" Music and Lyrics, Undated; 12457 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - "March" Score and Letter, 1932, undated; 12456 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - "Wearing of the Gray" Music and Individual Pieces, Undated; 12455 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Sheet Music--Various, Undated; 12454 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Sheet Music--"Pro Patria et Gloria", Undated; 12453 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Drum Corps--Roll Book, 1870-1893; 12452 (Volume 364)
  - Drum Corps--Minute Book, 1870-1887; 12451 (Volume 365)
  - Drum Corps--Minute Book, 1887-1917; 12450 (Volume 366)
  - Drum Corps--Account Book--Treasurer Book, 1879-1914; 12449 (Volume 367)
  - Band--Descriptive Book, 1908-1911; 12448 (Volume 368)
  - Band--Descriptive Book, 1911; 12447 (Volume 369)
  - Field Music--Account Book, 1893-1914; 12446 (Volume 370)
  - Seventh Regiment Quick Steps--Music, C.S. Grafulla, 1873-1876; 12445 (Volume 371)
  - "The Gallant Seventh" by John Philip Sousa, 1922; 12444 (Volume 372)
- Series XI: Recreational Activities, 1873-1950, 12416
  This series contains material related to the Rifle Club and athletic activities of the 7th Regiment.
  - Subseries 1: Rifle Club, 1879-1947, 12426
    The bulk of Rifle Club material relates to the 7th Regiment's matches with the Queen's Westminster Volunteers in 1905 and 1906. This includes the files of Capt. B.B. McAlpin which contain telegrams, ephemera and clippings for the 1905 match in England. Also found in this subseries is a scrapbook for the 1906 match. Other Rifle Club material includes bulletins, correspondence, minutes, programs, record and score books. See Series XIV for a photo album of the 1905 Queen's Westminsters match.
    - Bulletins, Correspondence, Minutes, 1875-1947; 12442 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Programs, 1878-1934; 12441 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Queen's Westminsters Match, London--Capt. B.B. McAlpin Files, Correspondence, 1905, [1905]; 12440 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Queen's Westminsters Match, London--Capt. B.B. McAlpin Files, Ephemera, 1905, [1905]; 12439 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Queen's Westminsters Match, London--Capt. B.B. McAlpin Files, Ephemera, 1905, [1905]; 12438 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Queen's Westminsters Match, London--Capt. B.B. McAlpin Files, Clippings, 1905, [1905]; 12437 (Box 40, Folder 6)